<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Elowen - Science</title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend-tags/science/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowentao.com"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-01-23T15:53:54+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://elowentao.com/focus-blend-tags/science/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Efficiency asymmetry: Scientists report fundamental asymmetry between heating and cooling</title>
        <published>2024-01-23T15:53:54+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-23T15:53:54+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/efficiency-asymmetry-scientists-report-fundamental-asymmetry-between-heating-and-cooling/"/>
        <id>https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/efficiency-asymmetry-scientists-report-fundamental-asymmetry-between-heating-and-cooling/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/efficiency-asymmetry-scientists-report-fundamental-asymmetry-between-heating-and-cooling/">&lt;p&gt;According to conventional wisdom, a system placed in an environment with a different temperature tends to relax to the temperature of the latter, mediated by the flows of heat or matter that are set solely by the temperature difference. It is becoming clear, however, that thermal relaxation is much more intricate when temperature changes push the system far from thermodynamic equilibrium. Here, by using an optically trapped colloidal particle, we show that microscale systems under such conditions heat up faster than they cool down. We find that between any pair of temperatures, heating is not only faster than cooling but the respective processes, in fact, evolve along fundamentally distinct pathways, which we explain with a new theoretical framework that we call thermal kinematics. Our results change the view of thermalization at the microscale and will have a strong impact on energy-conversion applications and thermal management of microscopic devices, particularly in the operation of Brownian heat engines.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;按照传统的观点，一个系统被置于不同温度的环境中，会倾向于放松到后者的温度，这完全是由温差所决定的热流或物质流促成的。然而，当温度变化使系统远离热力学平衡状态时，热松弛现象就会变得更加复杂。在这里，我们通过使用光学捕获胶体粒子，证明了微尺度系统在这种条件下升温比降温更快。我们发现，在任何一对温度之间，升温不仅比降温快，而且各自的过程实际上是沿着根本不同的路径演化的。我们的研究结果改变了人们对微观尺度热化的看法，将对微观设备的能量转换应用和热管理，尤其是布朗热机的运行产生重大影响。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
