<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Elowen - Asia</title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend-tags/asia/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowentao.com"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-01-26T14:52:26+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://elowentao.com/focus-blend-tags/asia/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>China&#x27;s population drops for second year, with record low birth rate</title>
        <published>2024-01-26T14:52:26+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-26T14:52:26+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/china-s-population-drops-for-second-year-with-record-low-birth-rate/"/>
        <id>https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/china-s-population-drops-for-second-year-with-record-low-birth-rate/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/china-s-population-drops-for-second-year-with-record-low-birth-rate/">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China&#x27;s population drops 0.15% y&#x2F;y in 2023&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Birth rate at new low, death rate at highest since 1974&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total new births drop 5.7% to 9.02 mln&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total deaths rise 6.6% to 11.1 mln&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Exclusive: China&#x27;s cabinet curbs debt growth in 12 &quot;high risk&quot; regions - sources</title>
        <published>2024-01-26T10:33:53+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:33:53+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/exclusive-china-s-cabinet-curbs-debt-growth-in-12-high-risk-regions-sources/"/>
        <id>https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/exclusive-china-s-cabinet-curbs-debt-growth-in-12-high-risk-regions-sources/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/exclusive-china-s-cabinet-curbs-debt-growth-in-12-high-risk-regions-sources/">&lt;p&gt;China&#x27;s cabinet has restricted the ability of local governments in 12 heavily indebted regions to take on new debt and placed limits on what new state-funded projects they can launch, three sources with knowledge of the matter said.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;三位知情人士透露，国务院已经限制了 12 个重债地区的地方政府举借新债的能力，并对它们可以启动哪些新的国家资助项目做出了限制。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 12 regions, which cover a wide swathe of the nation, will only be allowed to take on specified projects, such as those approved by the central government, the sources said. Other projects, such new railway stations and power plants, will not be permitted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;消息人士称，这 12 个地区覆盖了全国大部分地区，它们将只被允许承担特定项目，如中央政府批准的项目。其他项目，如新火车站和发电厂，将不被允许。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The order also specifies that debt growth of local government financing vehicles (LGFVs) should not be higher than average loan growth rates of the corporate sector in the province where the LGFVs are located, two of the sources said.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;其中两位消息人士说，该命令还规定，地方政府融资工具（LGFV）的债务增长率不得高于地方政府融资工具所在省份企业部门的平均贷款增长率。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While central government debt is only 21% OF GDP, local debt reached 92 trillion yuan ($12.58 trillion), or 76% of the country&#x27;s economic output in 2022, up from 62.2% in 2019. The massive piles of debt highlights local governments&#x27; financial stress, fuelling concerns of a systemic financial crisis.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;中央政府债务仅占 GDP 的 21%，而地方债务却达到 92 万亿元（12.58 万亿美元），占 2022 年全国经济产出的 76%，高于 2019 年的 62.2%。巨额债务凸显了地方政府的财政压力，加剧了人们对系统性金融危机的担忧。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;注：&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;原新闻发布日期为 2023 年 10 月 25 日&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;这 12 个省份分别是天津市、内蒙古自治区、辽宁省、吉林省、黑龙江省、广西壮族自治区、重庆市、贵州省、云南省、甘肃省、青海省、宁夏回族自治区。（引自 &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;economy.caixin.com&#x2F;2024-01-23&#x2F;102159360.html&quot;&gt;财新网&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;）&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Senior China Envoy Dismisses Qin Gang Removal as ‘Not Uncommon’</title>
        <published>2024-01-24T16:31:47+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-24T16:31:47+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/senior-china-envoy-dismisses-qin-gang-removal-as-not-uncommon/"/>
        <id>https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/senior-china-envoy-dismisses-qin-gang-removal-as-not-uncommon/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/senior-china-envoy-dismisses-qin-gang-removal-as-not-uncommon/">&lt;p&gt;An investigation found Qin had an affair while serving as the US ambassador that could have endangered national security, the Wall Street Journal reported, though no inquiry has been announced.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;据《华尔街日报》报道，一项调查发现，秦在担任美国大使期间有外遇，可能危及国家安全，但目前尚未宣布任何调查。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qin’s downfall came as Chinese leader Xi Jinping embarked on a sweeping purge of the military, which included sacking then defense minister Li Shangfu in October. That graft probe ensnared more than a dozen senior defense officials over some six months, in what may be China’s largest crackdown on its armed forces.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;秦的下台正值中国领导人习近平开始对军队进行全面整顿之际，其中包括在 10 月份解除时任国防部长李尚福的职务。在大约六个月的时间里，十多名高级国防官员被卷入这场贪腐调查，这可能是中国对军队进行的最大规模的镇压。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lack of transparency about Qin and the situation in the military have added to investor worries about China’s opaque decision-making as the world’s second-largest economy grapples with a slowdown that’s now among the reasons the stock market is sliding.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在世界第二大经济体努力应对经济放缓之际，秦国和军方情况的不透明加剧了投资者对中国决策不透明的担忧，这也是股市下滑的原因之一。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>China’s Provinces Mostly Target GDP Growth of 5% Or More in 2024</title>
        <published>2024-01-24T16:07:55+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-24T16:07:55+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/china-s-provinces-mostly-target-gdp-growth-of-5-or-more-in-2024/"/>
        <id>https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/china-s-provinces-mostly-target-gdp-growth-of-5-or-more-in-2024/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/china-s-provinces-mostly-target-gdp-growth-of-5-or-more-in-2024/">&lt;p&gt;Top officials have signaled they likely won’t roll out massive stimulus now due to concerns about creating systemic risks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;高层官员已经表示，由于担心引发系统性风险，他们现在可能不会推出大规模刺激政策。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Why China Is Considering Rarely Used Special Bonds to Stimulate Its Economy</title>
        <published>2024-01-22T15:58:42+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-22T15:58:42+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/why-china-is-considering-rarely-used-special-bonds-to-stimulate-its-economy/"/>
        <id>https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/why-china-is-considering-rarely-used-special-bonds-to-stimulate-its-economy/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/why-china-is-considering-rarely-used-special-bonds-to-stimulate-its-economy/">&lt;p&gt;China sells general bonds every year to fill the spending gap in its budget. Special sovereign bonds have been issued on rare occasions to raise cash for specific purposes. These — unlike general bonds — are not included in the country’s deficit calculations. Special bonds can also be approved on an ad-hoc basis, such as when the Standing Committee of the National People’s Congress — the Communist Party-controlled parliament that oversees government borrowing — meets every two months or so. In contrast, general bonds in most cases need to be factored into the budget and receive approval at the annual NPC meeting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;中国每年都会出售一般债券，以填补预算支出缺口。在极少数情况下，中国会发行特别主权债券，为特定用途筹集现金。与一般债券不同，这些债券不计入国家赤字计算。特别债券也可以临时批准，例如在全国人民代表大会常务委员会（共产党控制的议会，负责监督政府借贷）每两个月左右召开一次会议时。相比之下，一般债券在大多数情况下需要计入预算，并在每年的全国人大会议上获得批准。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special bonds can help Beijing keep local debt risks under control. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;专项债券可以帮助北京控制地方债务风险。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central government has a much healthier balance sheet than local authorities. The amount of sovereign debt outstanding is around $4 trillion, less than a third of the local debt stockpile including some borrowing by local government financing vehicles, according to Bloomberg calculations based on data from the Ministry of Finance and the International Monetary Fund.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;与地方政府相比，中央政府的资产负债表要健康得多。据彭博社根据财政部和国际货币基金组织的数据计算，中国未偿还的主权债务约为 4 万亿美元，不到地方债务（包括地方政府融资工具的部分借款）的三分之一。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>China Buys Near-Record $40 Billion of Chip Gear to Beat US Curbs</title>
        <published>2024-01-22T15:50:15+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-22T15:50:15+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/china-buys-near-record-40-billion-of-chip-gear-to-beat-us-curbs/"/>
        <id>https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/china-buys-near-record-40-billion-of-chip-gear-to-beat-us-curbs/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/china-buys-near-record-40-billion-of-chip-gear-to-beat-us-curbs/">&lt;p&gt;Imports of the machinery used to make computer chips rose 14% in 2023 to almost $40 billion — the second largest amount by value on record in data going back to 2015, according to Bloomberg calculations based on official customs data. The increase came despite a 5.5% drop in total imports last year, underscoring the importance that the Chinese government and the nation’s chip industry have placed on becoming self-sufficient.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据彭博社基于官方海关数据的计算，2023 年用于制造计算机芯片的机械进口额增长了 14%，达到近 400 亿美元，是 2015 年以来有记录的第二大进口额。尽管去年的进口总额下降了 5.5%，但这一增长仍凸显了中国政府和中国芯片行业对实现自给自足的重视&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even before those curbs came into effect, Dutch company ASML Holding NV had canceled shipments of some of its top-of-the-line machines to China at the request of the US government, Bloomberg reported earlier this month. The cancellations came weeks before export bans on the high-end chipmaking equipment came into effect.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;据彭博社本月早些时候报道，甚至在这些禁令生效之前，荷兰公司 ASML Holding NV 就已经应美国政府的要求，取消了部分顶级设备对中国的发货。在高端芯片制造设备出口禁令生效前几周，ASML 就取消了对华发货。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>China Stock Selloff Worsens as Hong Kong Index Nears 19-Year Low</title>
        <published>2024-01-22T15:31:35+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-22T15:31:35+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/china-stock-selloff-worsens-as-hong-kong-index-nears-19-year-low/"/>
        <id>https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/china-stock-selloff-worsens-as-hong-kong-index-nears-19-year-low/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/china-stock-selloff-worsens-as-hong-kong-index-nears-19-year-low/">&lt;p&gt;The Hang Seng China Enterprises Index fell as much as 2.2%, edging closer to a level unseen since 2005 and making it one of Asia’s worst-performing key indexes. Chinese tech behemoths including Meituan and Tencent Holdings Ltd. led the declines.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;恒生中国企业指数跌幅高达 2.2%，逼近 2005 年以来的最低水平，成为亚洲表现最差的主要指数之一。美团和腾讯控股有限公司等中国科技巨头领跌。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gauge of Chinese stocks listed in Hong Kong has lost nearly 13% so far this year, while the S&amp;amp;P 500 has gained 1.5%. HSCEI is the worst performer globally among more than 90 equity indexes tracked by Bloomberg.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;今年迄今为止，在香港上市的中国股票指数下跌了近 13%，而标准普尔 500 指数则上涨了 1.5%。在彭博社跟踪的 90 多个股票指数中，国企指数是全球表现最差的。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A confluence of factors have driven the swoon in Chinese stocks since 2024 began, ranging from a deepening housing slump to stubborn deflationary pressures, as well as Beijing’s reluctance to use aggressive monetary and fiscal measures to revive growth. Uncertainties about the trajectory of US interest rates, the threat of an imminent selloff in local stock derivatives and concerns about tighter regulatory oversight have added to the pessimism.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;自 2024 年开始以来，中国股市暴跌是多种因素共同作用的结果，其中既有不断加深的房地产低迷，也有顽固的通货紧缩压力，还有中国政府不愿采取激进的货币和财政措施来重振经济增长。美国利率走势的不确定性、本地股票衍生品即将大跌的威胁以及对监管趋严的担忧，都加剧了市场的悲观情绪。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The politics of Apple’s AirDrop security flaw</title>
        <published>2024-01-21T16:19:26+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-21T16:19:26+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/the-politics-of-apple-s-airdrop-security-flaw/"/>
        <id>https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/the-politics-of-apple-s-airdrop-security-flaw/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/the-politics-of-apple-s-airdrop-security-flaw/">&lt;p&gt;Apple placed heavy restrictions on AirDrop use in China, particularly on messages received from outside a user’s contacts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在抗议活动最激烈的时候，苹果对 AirDrop 在中国的使用施加了严格限制，尤其是对从用户联系人以外收到的信息。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Johns Hopkins cryptographer Matt Green tells it, researchers had found a way around that system as early as 2019, reported it to Apple, and published their findings two years later. As Green makes clear, there’s a way to build this system that avoids the bug, but it’s processor-intensive and Apple hasn’t implemented it. This meant the vulnerability stayed open for years, to the point that it can be exploited by local authorities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰·霍普金斯大学的密码学家马特·格林（Matt Green）告诉我们，研究人员早在 2019 年就找到了绕过该系统的方法，并将其报告给了苹果公司，两年后他们公布了研究结果。格林明确指出，有一种方法可以构建这个系统来避免漏洞，但这种方法需要大量的处理器，而且苹果公司还没有实施。这意味着该漏洞多年来一直处于开放状态，以至于地方当局可以利用它。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple has mostly complied, championing new Foxconn sites outside of China, most notably in India and Vietnam.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;苹果公司大多遵从了要求，在中国以外的地区，尤其是印度和越南新建了富士康工厂。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, Beijing may no longer be interested in making things easy for Apple.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;到了某个时候，中国政府可能不再愿意让苹果公司好过。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>中国全力发展绿色产业，以刺激疲软的经济</title>
        <published>2024-01-19T17:04:27+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-19T17:04:27+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/zhong-guo-quan-li-fa-zhan-lu-se-chan-ye-yi-ci-ji-pi-ruan-de-jing-ji/"/>
        <id>https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/zhong-guo-quan-li-fa-zhan-lu-se-chan-ye-yi-ci-ji-pi-ruan-de-jing-ji/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/zhong-guo-quan-li-fa-zhan-lu-se-chan-ye-yi-ci-ji-pi-ruan-de-jing-ji/">&lt;p&gt;经济学家认为未来有两大障碍。
其一是房地产在中国经济中的比重已经非常之高，要取代它并不容易。这意味着预期中的再平衡将伴随着经济的阵痛，在此期间中国的经济增长将比家庭、企业和投资者预期的要疲弱得多。
其次，许多国家，尤其是美国和欧洲等大型市场，所展现出的对进口中国工业复兴成果的兴趣并不是那么高，甚至一些市场已经提高了对中国产品的壁垒。这可能引发新一轮针锋相对的保护主义，或给全球经济带来持续的压力。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;日本、韩国和台湾在变得擅长高科技制造之际，基本上把低端制造业拱手让给了成本更低的地区，而中国则不同，不仅要制造飞机和半导体等高端产品，也不放弃制造玩具和家具等中国几十年来一直擅长的产品，从而巩固其世界工厂的地位。根据联合国 (United Nations) 的数据，2022 年，中国占全球制造业的 31%，而美国仅占 16%。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;位于伦敦的 GlobalData TS Lombard 的首席中国经济学家 Rory Green 说，中国政府所青睐的一些制造领域全加到一起，最多可能占到中国 GDP 的 10%。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“中国经济仍然极其依赖建筑活动，”凯投宏观 (Capital Economics) 驻新加坡的中国经济主管 Julian Evans-Pritchard 说。“中国经济之所以仍在以 5% 的速度增长，并不是因为电动汽车出口蓬勃发展。其体量实在是太小了。”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这与高盛 (Goldman Sachs) 经济学家的看法不谋而合，据他们计算，未来几年对“新三样”产业的投资将不足以抵消中国面临的更广泛挑战所构成的拖累。在最近的一份报告中，他们估计，即使考虑到对电动汽车、电池和可再生能源领域的巨额投资，房地产行业的持续低迷和传统汽车产量的下降也将对年增长率构成 0.5 个百分点的拖累，直到 2027 年。他们发现，对就业的净影响也将是负面的，因为与现代制造业相比，建筑业往往能吸纳更多就业。该投行预计，今年中国经济的年增长率将放缓至 4.5% 左右，到 2027 年将放缓至 3.7%。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;尽管印度等一些国家正在考虑对某些中国产品实施更严格的限制，以保护本国的新兴产业，但其他国家可能将中国产品视为负担得起的西方高科技产品的替代品。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Did China’s Economy Really Grow 5.2% in 2023? Not All Agree</title>
        <published>2024-01-18T11:20:38+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-18T11:20:38+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/did-china-s-economy-really-grow-5-2-in-2023-not-all-agree/"/>
        <id>https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/did-china-s-economy-really-grow-5-2-in-2023-not-all-agree/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://elowentao.com/focus-blend/did-china-s-economy-really-grow-5-2-in-2023-not-all-agree/">&lt;p&gt;Independent Data Shows China Domestic Travel Surge in 2023&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;独立数据显示 2023 年中国国内旅游人数激增&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doubts about China’s official investment statistics — which measure spending on things like housing, factories and infrastructure — have been fueled by frequent revisions in recent years, and the latest data implies an unusually large adjustment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;近年来，中国官方投资统计数据（用于衡量住房、工厂和基础设施等方面的支出）频繁被修正，这加剧了人们对中国官方投资统计数据的疑虑，而最新数据则意味着一次不同寻常的大幅调整。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doubts about China’s GDP data tend to spike when the economy slows, with skepticism peaking after Beijing reported 2022 growth at 3% despite widespread lockdowns. Coronavirus controls that year reduced GDP by 3.9%, according to a forthcoming paper in the China Economic Review based on data from nighttime lights tracked from space.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对中国 GDP 数据的怀疑往往会在经济放缓时激增，在中国政府报告 2022 年经济增长为 3% 之后，怀疑情绪达到顶峰，尽管封锁范围很广。根据即将发表在《中国经济评论》上的一篇论文，基于从太空追踪的夜间灯光数据，当年的冠状病毒控制使 GDP 减少了 3.9%。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around a decade ago, the “Li Keqiang index” was in vogue, named after China’s former premier, who was cited saying he relied on estimates of electricity use, rail freight volumes and bank loan growth as a proxy for GDP. But it’s fallen out of favor, because China’s economy now consists mainly of services, with heavy industry having a smaller role.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;大约十年前，&amp;quot;李克强指数 &amp;quot;曾风靡一时，该指数以中国前总理的名字命名，他曾被引述说，他依靠用电量、铁路货运量和银行贷款增长的估计值来代表国内生产总值。但是，由于中国经济目前主要由服务业构成，重工业所占比重较小，&amp;quot;李克强指数 &amp;quot;已不再受青睐。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
