<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Elowen - Life</title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://elowen.life/focus-blend-tags/life/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowen.life"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-01-21T19:34:40+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://elowen.life/focus-blend-tags/life/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The Real Reason You’re Paying for So Many Subscriptions</title>
        <published>2024-01-21T19:34:40+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-21T19:34:40+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowen.life/focus-blend/the-real-reason-you-re-paying-for-so-many-subscriptions/"/>
        <id>https://elowen.life/focus-blend/the-real-reason-you-re-paying-for-so-many-subscriptions/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://elowen.life/focus-blend/the-real-reason-you-re-paying-for-so-many-subscriptions/">&lt;p&gt;That, as it turns out, is one of the hidden forces behind the subscription economy: Americans spend billions of dollars on stuff they have forgotten about. A dirty little secret behind many of the world’s most popular subscription services is that they owe part of their success to our lack of attention.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;事实证明，这是订阅经济背后的一个隐藏力量：美国人在他们已经忘记的东西上花费了数十亿美元。世界上许多最受欢迎的订阅服务背后的一个肮脏小秘密是，它们的成功部分归功于我们的注意力不集中。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The Alchemy of Good Questions</title>
        <published>2024-01-20T17:04:22+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-20T17:04:22+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowen.life/focus-blend/the-alchemy-of-good-questions/"/>
        <id>https://elowen.life/focus-blend/the-alchemy-of-good-questions/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://elowen.life/focus-blend/the-alchemy-of-good-questions/">&lt;p&gt;When you ask good questions, you get good answers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当你提出好问题时，你就会得到好答案。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asking good questions is a bit like being an alchemist. They have a transformative power that allows you to transform any conversation into a source of actionable information and creative insights.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;提出好问题有点像炼金术士。它们有一种转化的力量，能让你把任何对话转化为可操作的信息和创造性见解的源泉。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are five guidelines to keep or to start asking good questions:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know your purpose&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. It’s easy to get distracted during a conversation. Try to make sure that every question you ask helps you gather either facts or your interlocutor’s opinion. Avoid empty questions to fill the time. Genuinely try to know more about them, and frame your questions accordingly.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start by listening&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. In the classic &lt;em&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, Dale Carnegie advised to “be a good listener” and to “ask questions the other person will enjoy answering.” More than eighty years later, his advice still holds true. You can’t ask good questions if you don’t listen to what the person has to say.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interrupt wisely&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. It’s not about never interrupting the person you’re chatting with. It’s about ending fewer sentences with a period, and more with a question mark. Don’t worry about asking the wrong question. Not asking enough is more detrimental to building a relationship than asking one poorly phrased question. That being said…&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use the right wording&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Avoid leading questions and use a neutral tone instead. Refrain hinting at your opinion or the answer you’d like to get. If you want honest opinions or accurate information, don’t prime your interlocutor with loaded questions. Keep them open ended so they have the option of giving you an answer you didn’t expect. (closed questions are often used in manipulative surveys to get the results needed to support a specific agenda)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build a hierarchy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Follow general questions with specific ones, focus your questions so they ask one thing at a time, and use something in the answer you got to frame your next question. This will help the conversation flow more naturally.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以下是五条提问指南：&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;目标明确&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;：在对话的海洋中，不要迷失方向。每个问题都应该是你探索真相或了解对方观点的桨。避免只为消磨时间而提问，真心实意地探寻对方的世界，使你的问题成为探索之光。&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;倾听先行&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;：在《如何赢得朋友和影响他人》（How to Win Friends and Influence People）这本传世经典中，戴尔·卡耐基告诉我们要“成为一名优秀的倾听者”，并“提出让对方乐于回答的问题”。即使时过境迁，这个建议依然有效。不倾听，就无法精准提问。&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;智慧打断&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;：这并不是说永远不打断正在和你聊天的人。而是减少句末的句号，多用问号。让对话少一些句号，多一些问号。不要担心问错问题。问得不够比问一个措辞不当的问题更不利于建立关系。&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;措辞得当&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;：避免引导性问题，保持语气中立。不要流露出你想听到的答案，如果你追求真实和准确，就别让问题带有预设立场。开放式的问题能带来意想不到的答案。（封闭式问题常见于为了特定目的而设的调查中）&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;构建层次&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;：先提出一般性问题，再跟进具体的问题。每次只探讨一个点，用前一个回答作为下一个问题的起点。这样，对话就能像溪流一样自然流淌。&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important guideline to remember is simply to ask more questions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最重要的准则很简单，那就是多提问。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Corporations Are Not To Be Loved</title>
        <published>2024-01-19T17:30:09+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-19T17:30:09+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://elowen.life/focus-blend/corporations-are-not-to-be-loved/"/>
        <id>https://elowen.life/focus-blend/corporations-are-not-to-be-loved/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://elowen.life/focus-blend/corporations-are-not-to-be-loved/">&lt;p&gt;But I need to remember, now and again, that Apple is a corporation, and corporations aren’t people, and they can’t love you back. You wouldn’t love GE or Exxon or Comcast — and you shouldn’t love Apple. It’s not an exception to the rule: there are no exceptions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但我得时不时提醒自己，苹果是一家公司，公司不是人，它们无法回应你的爱。你不会爱通用电气、埃克森或康卡斯特，你也不应该爱苹果。这不是规则的例外：没有例外。&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
